A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Religious Interests, Series N FA323
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Young Men's Bible Class
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - The Club, January 1904? (Box 97, Folder 790)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Constitution (Box 97, Folder 791)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Pamphlet Announcements, circa 1922-1924 (Box 97, Folder 792)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Reports and Leader Lists, 1904-1914 (Box 97, Folder 793)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Membership Campaign, 1917? (Box 97, Folder 794)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Young Ladies' Bible Class - Miscellaneous, 1914-1930 (Box 97, Folder 795)
    Membership, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous (Box 103, Folder 824)
    "J. D. Rockefeller, Jr., and his Bible Class." "The Toledo Weekly Blade," April 4, 1901. Negative (photostat) copy.
- Bibles
  - Bibles - "Comprehensive Reference Bible" - King James Version (Box 98, Folder 796)
    Handwritten inscription to Nelson W. Aldrich, inside front cover.
  - Bibles - Paper sent from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Nelson A. Rockefeller - Photocopy of a Comic (Box 98, Folder 797)
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - Cooperstown, New York: H. & E. Phinney's Stereotype Edition, 1834 - King James Version (Box 98, Folder 798)
    Avery Bible, "This Bible came into my possession on the death of my mother Mrs. Eliza Davison Rockefeller in March 1889 - John Davison Rockefeller" William A. Rockefeller family register.
  - Bibles - "Family Bible Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Sr.", 3 pages (Box 99, Folder 799)
    a. Marriages b. Deaths c. Dedication Sheet (copy of inscription)
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - Philadelphia: E. H. Butler & Company, 1859 - King James Version (Box 99, Folder 800)
    Inscription inside front cover: "Laura C. Spelman. A Marriage Gift. From her Father, September 8, 1864. This 'Family Bible' was given to her son, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., on his 40th birthday January 29th, 1914 - By his mother, Laura Spelman Rockefeller" John D. Rockefeller family register.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: Carlton and Porter, 1857 - King James Version (Box 100, Folder 801)
    Handwritten inscription underleafe to title page, "Abbie Greene." Family Bible.
  - Bibles - "Le Nouveau Testament" - New York: Societe Biblique Americaine, 1880 - En Francaise ("The New Testament" - New York: American Bible Society - In French) (Box 100, Folder 802)
    Handwritten inscription, underleaf to title page: "John D. Rockefeller Jr. Forest Hill September 28, 1882"
  - Bibles - "Pictorial Bible" - London: Samuel Bagster and Sons, n.d. - King James Version (Box 100, Folder 803)
    Inscription to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on underleaf to title page.
  - Bibles - "Polyglot Bible" - London: Samuel Bagster and Sons, n.d. - English Version (Box 100, Folder 804)
    Laura S. Rockefeller. "This was my mother's Bible which always lay on the table in the library at 4 West 54th Street, New York. John D. Rockefeller April 1, 1946." Used by Nelson A. Rockefeller for his inauguration as Governor of New York in 1959, 1963, 1967, 1971, and when he was sworn in as Vice President in 1974. "Love never faileth" bookmark.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - London: George E. Eyre and William Spottiswoode (The Queen's Printers), 1858 (Box 100, Folder 805)
    "Presented to Miss Abby P. T. Greene for reciting 1000 Scripture verses in the Beruf Coug Sabbath School in the year ending January 2nd 1859."
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: American Bible Society, 1859 (Box 100, Folder 806)
    Inscription in pencil, underleaf to title page, appears to say "J. Aldrich."
  - Bibles - "Twentieth Century New Testament" - New York: Fleming H. Revell Company, 1904 - Modern English Revised (Box 101, Folder 807)
    Inscription on facing title page: "John D. Rockefeller, Jr. With love, from Mother - on his birthday January 29th 1906." Piece of paper with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s notes on the Bible. Card from Laura Spelman Rockefeller.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: Oxford University Press, n.d. - King James Version (Box 101, Folder 808)
    Inscription: John D. Rockefeller, Jr. "To our Honary President Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. A token of Love and Affection from the Officers and Members of the Men's Bible Class of the Park Avenue Baptist Church. Robert McLaughlin President, A. Robt. Munro Secretary New York May 10. 1926." John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s notes about the Bible (two pieces of paper).
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible and Cyclopedic Concordance" - New York: Oxford University Press, 1947 - King James Version (Box 101, Folder 809)
    "Martha B. Rockefeller" engraved on front cover. Inscribed John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to wife, 1954.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: Oxford University Press, n.d. Sunday School Teacher's Edition, with References and Maps (Box 101, Folder 810)
    Inscription in front cover: John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1884. "This Bible was given to me when I was ten years old, undoubtedly by my mother, and was used by me all my early life. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. April 1, 1946." Poem glued in front. Paper with notes.
  - Bibles - "Twentieth Century New Testament" - New York: Fleming H. Revell Company, 1904 (Box 101, Folder 811)
    Inscriptions in front: Lucy M. Spelman; to E. C. Carder from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Note clipped on outside front cover.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1912 - "An Improved Edition," based on the Bible Union Version (Box 101, Folder 812)
    Inscription: "To John Davison Rockefeller Jr. on his 39th birthday, January 29th 1913. From his mother - Laura Spelman Rockefeller. New York City. "All things are yours - and ye are Christ's and Christ is God's." 1st Cor. 3C. - 21st and 25 V's." John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s notes on the Bible (two pieces of paper).
  - Bibles - "Scriptures" - The New Testament - New York: American Bible Society, 1921 - Revised Translation - Large Print Edition (Box 101, Folder 813)
    Inscription: Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. "To our Good Friends Who Love and practice these beautiful teachings in their daily walks of Life. Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. New York - With Loving Good Wishes. Compliments - Clarence H. Howards. May 1st 1922 SLouis"
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: Oxford University Press, 1901 - King James Version (Box 101A, Folder 814)
    "John D. & Abby A. Rockefeller. With love from Mother Rockefeller - Christmas 1904. "For Thou has delivered my soul from death, mine eyes from tears, and my feet from failing."" John D. Rockefeller, Jr. family register (Grandchildren listed). Used for Winthrop Rockefeller's inauguration as governor of Arkansas, 1967 and 1969.
  - Bibles - "Holy Bible" - New York: Oxford University Press, 1901 - King James Version (Box 101A, Folder 814)
- Legal Size and Oversize Material
  - Legal Size Material (Box 102, Folder 815)
    Salvation Army, Seaman's Church Institute, Billy Sunday, Young Men's Bible Class.
    See also Boxes 90-96, Folders 732-784.
  - Linen Covered Newspaper, Used by Fosdick, New York Daily Graphic (1881), Providence Paper Article on Nelson W. Aldrich (Box 103, Folder 830)